Elizabeth Campbell papers, circa 1964-1978
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
Elizabeth Campbell papers
1964-1978
C0132
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
0.25 linear feet (1 box)
The Elizabeth Campbell papers collection includes correspondence between Elizabeth Campbell and George Mason University Advisory Board officials, regarding the opening of a satellite campus in Arlington.
Campbell, Elizabeth
Biographical Information
Elizabeth Campbell, originally from North Carolina, attended Salem College and later Columbia University. In 1948 Mrs. Campbell was appointed to the Arlington County School Board and, in 1953, was the founder and first president of WETA-TV, a public television station serving Washington D.C. In 1987 she was awarded an Emmy for her work in public broadcasting. Additionally, Campbell served on the Board of Control for the acquisition of land for George Mason College in the 1960s and the Chairman of the Consortium for Continuing Higher Education Citizens Advisory Committee in the 1970s. Elizabeth Campbell passed away in 2004 at the age of 101.
Scope and Contents
The Elizabeth Campbell papers collection includes correspondence between Elizabeth Campbell and George Mason University Advisory Board officials, regarding Mrs. Campbell's appointment to the Board of Control for the acquisition of land for George Mason College.
The collection contains nine letters dated between 1964 and 1972, and one resolution recognizing Mrs. Campbell's commitment to the Continuing Higher Education Citizens Advisory Committee dated 1978. The letters pertain largely to Mrs. Campbell's appointment to the Board of Control, who was petitioning for land in Arlington, Virginia, on which to build a satellite campus.
Arrangement
All correspondence is contained in one series.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donor unknown.
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds
Index Terms
Geographical Names:
Fairfax (Va.); Virginia, Northern--History, Local.
Subjects:
Universities and colleges--History.; University extension--Virginia, Northern.
Contents List
- Edgar F. Shannon to Elizabeth Campbell, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Regarding Mrs. Campbell's appointment to the Advisory Committee for George Mason College, dated May 15th, 1964.
- Edgar F. Shannon to Elizabeth Campbell, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Regarding Mrs. Campbell's acceptance of membership on the Advisory Committee, dated June 26th, 1964.
- Elizabeth Campbell to Joseph L. Fisher, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  In reply to a letter accepting a position on the Board of Control for the Establishment of a Branch College in Northern Virginia, dated August 23rd 1965.
- Joseph L. Fisher to Elizabeth Campbell, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  The letter referenced in the previous file appointing Mrs. Campbell to the board, dated May 24th, 1965.
- Joseph L. Fisher to Elizabeth Campbell, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Regarding Mrs. Campbell's appointment to the board, dated September 3rd, 1965.
- Edgar F. Shannon to Elizabeth Campbell, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Regarding Mrs. Campbell's reappointment to the George Mason College Advisory Committee, dated June 30th 1967.
- Kenneth M. Haggerty to Elizabeth Campbell, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Regarding Mrs. Campbell's reappointment as Arlington's representative on the Board of Control, dated July 14th, 1969.
- James H. Clark to Elizabeth Campbell, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Letter thanking Mrs. Campbell for casting her ballot for the Board of Control Resolution, dated January 30th 1970.
- Dean E. Brundage to Mrs. Campbell, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  A letter inquiring as to whether Mrs. Campbell would be able to serve on the advisory committee for the Consortium for Continuing Higher Education in Northern Virginia, dated October 30th, 1972.
- A Resolution, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Resolution from the CCHENV board of directors acknowledging Mrs. Campbell's successful completion of her term of office, dated September 29th 1978